Tiago Henrique Costa Alves

② tiagohca.com

☑ tiagohcalves@gmail.com

? tiagohcalves

31 975345587

ABOUT ME

I'm a Tech Lead at Kunumi with experience in many fields of machine learning and data science, such as time-series prediction, anomaly detection, natural language processing and reinforcement learning, developing methods to analyze, model and get insights from all types of data, while also developing software to extract value from the models created. As a Data Scientist I was able to work developing tools and frameworks to boost other data scientists productivity, while also developing bank credit scoring models, medical assistance models and more. I'm also motivated by challenges and believe that a new problem is always an opportunity to learn and discover new solutions.

I have a Masters Degree in Computer Science by the Federal University of Minas Gerais (UFMG) with focus in Deep Learning where I studied Information Retrieval, Recommender Systems, Data Visualization and Machine Learning. While in college, I studied abroad for a year, in the University of Roma Tre, in Italy.

Professionally, I aim to become a personal and technical reference for my colleagues and those who are beginning in the field, while also positively impacting as many people as possible with my work.

EXPERIENCE

Kunumi Belo Horizonte, MG

Tech Lead

2019-01-01 to Present

- Team Leader, Project Manager, Data Scientist, and Machine Learning Engineer, with a broad range of
 activities, going from understanding the client's needs and translating them to the team, in order to deliver
 high-quality machine learning systems, to managing tasks using Agile development methodology, and finally
 bringing new promising technologies to the team.
- As a Data Scientist and Tech Lead I was able to work and manage projects in different business areas, such as credit scoring for a digital bank, risk prediction for a health insurance company and fuel optimization for a rail freight company. I also manage a project for developing new frameworks and tools in order to boost the company productivity.
- I was also engaged in managing activities company-wide, such as hiring new engineers, managing project allocation and developing internal courses to share knowledge across different teams.

Kunumi Belo Horizonte, MG

Data Scientist

2016-07-19 to 2018-12-31

 Acting as Data Scientist and Machine Learning Engineer, with a broad range of activities, from understanding the client's data and mining relevant information, to developing predictive models and delivering integrated software

Sydle Belo Horizonte, MG

Software Engineer

2016-01-02 to 2016-07-18

o Full-stack developer at a job search engine, applying technologies such as C#, .Net, AngularJS and Elastic-Search, along with HTML, JavaScript and CSS under a SCRUM methodology

Sydle Belo Horizonte, MG

Intern

2015-01-19 to 2015-12-31

• Full-stack developer at a job search engine, applying technologies such as C#, .Net, AngularJS and Elastic-Search, along with HTML, JavaScript and CSS under a SCRUM methodology

EDUCATION

Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais

Belo Horizonte, MG

- o Thesis: Dynamic Prediction of ICU Mortality Risk Using Domain Adaptation
- o Fields of Study: Deep Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Information Retrieval, Recommender Systems

CEFET-MG

Belo Horizonte, MG

2010-08-02 to 2016-01-13

Belo Horizonte, MG

August 2013 to July 2014

B.E. Degree in Computer Engineering Università degli Studi di Roma Tre

Exchange Student

SKILLS

- o Time-Series analysis (modeling, feature engineering, evaluation)
- o Anomaly Detection (unsupervised, semi-supervised and supervised methods)
- NLP (feature engineering + statistical methods and deep learning)
- o Reinforcement Learning (Actor-critic, Deep Q-Learning)
- o Deep Learning (keras, pytorch, recurrent and convolutional networks, pre-trained models)
- o Statistical Learning (Gradient Boosting, classification, regression and clustering methods)
- Explainability, interpretation and causality for machine learning
- o Deploy frameworks (flask, django, mlflow)
- o AWS (ec2, fargate, s3, cloudwatch, athena)
- o Information Retrieval (Crawling, scrapping, indexing, search engines)
- o C# and .NET
- o Relational Databases (MySQL, SQLServer, Oracle) and NoSQL (ElasticSearch, DynamoDB)
- o Software Development (Software structure, micro-services, SCRUM, etc)

LANGUAGES

- o Portuguese (Native)
- o English (TOEFL 2013 96/120 and TOEFL IPT 2016 C1)
- o Italian (Italian Course at Rome B2)